Guide to the Elizabeth Hatcher Conner Collection, 1933-1945 UA.30.01.0071
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Elizabeth Hatcher Conner Collection
1933-1945
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Conner, Elizabeth Hatcher, 1918-2016
Conner, Robert W., 1914-2007
UA.30.01.0071
2.0 Linear Feet
Elizabeth Hatcher, Duke University class of 1939, was a photographer and member of the Explorers' Club, along with her future husband Bob Conner. The collection includes many photographs, a scrapbook, letters, and other materials documenting campus life at Duke in the late 1930s.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Original nitrate negatives may not be viewed in the reading room. Some materials may have already been digitized. To arrange for the digitization of other materials, please contact University Archives staff.
Collection Overview
The collection includes photographs, letters, a scrapbook, and memorabilia from Elizabeth Hatcher and Bob Conner's time at Duke. Photographic negatives and prints depict Duke's campus, Explorers' Club activities, students in dorms and on campus, and other scenes; individuals in these images include Elizabeth Hatcher, Bob Conner, Dean Mary Alice Baldwin, Louis Orr, and a woman who may be Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans (then Mary Duke Biddle). Other materials include letters written by Bob Conner to his mother in the mid-1930s, Bob Conner's diary written during a trip to find and identify orchids in Florida and Georgia in 1936, Elizabeth Hatcher's scrapbook of her sophomore year (which includes clippings, football game programs, invitations, and other materials), newsclippings featuring Elizabeth Hatcher, Bob Conner's dink (freshmen beanie), and other materials.
Photographic negatives are primarily celluloid nitrate.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth "Lib" Hatcher was born August 2, 1918, in High Point, North Carolina, to Pearl Sink and Edgar A. Hatcher. She entered the Woman's College at Duke University in 1936, majoring in Zoology. She became a photographer for the Chanticleer and developed her own photographs in her room in Bassett dormitory. She also joined the Explorer's Club, a co-educational hiking group chaperoned by Dean Mary Alice Baldwin of the Woman's College. Lib Hatcher graduated in 1939 and married Bob Conner in 1940. She taught Biology at Smith College and later at High Point College.
Robert (Bob) Conner was born September 8, 1914, in Pennsylvania, to Floyd and Helen Conner. He enrolled in Duke University in 1933, studying Civil Engineering, and attended classes off and on due to the Depression. He served in the Seabees during World War 2 and later became an architect.
The couple had three children: Susan, Christine, and William (Bill). Bob Conner died in 2007. Elizabeth Hatcher Conner died January 27, 2016 in High Point, North Carolina.
Related Materials
Elizabeth Hatcher Conner Flickr photo stream, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Virginia Passmore Beaujean Scrapbook, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Elizabeth Mapes Horner papers, University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Explorers' Club Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Woman's College Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Elizabeth Hatcher Conner Collection was received by the University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2010 and 2016.
Accessions described in this finding aid: UA2010.0031, UA2016.008, and UA2016.0019.
Women college students -- North Carolina -- Durham; Conner, Elizabeth Hatcher, 1918-2016; Conner, Robert W., 1914-2007; Duke University. Woman's College -- Students; Duke University. Explorers' Club; Duke University -- Students
- Photographic prints, 1934-1939
  - Photographs, circa 1930s, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Commencement photographs, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Duke, 1934-1939 (Box 1)
  - Explorer's Club and general Duke photographs, 1936-1937 (Box 1)
- Photographic negatives, 1935-1945; 2
  Conditions Governing Access
  The majority of these negatives are cellulose nitrate and may not be accessed in the reading room. Links to digitized versions of the nitrate negatives are provided.
  - Freshman Day, 1935 (Box 4, Image UA30010071-N-0001 - UA30010071-N-0013)
  - Duke, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Image UA30010071-N-0014 - UA30010071-N-0082)
  - Duke and Smith, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Image UA30010071-N-0083 - UA30010071-N-0112)
  - Explorers Club, undated (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0113 - UA30010071-N-0198)
  - Duke, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0199 - UA30010071-N-0222)
  - Explorers Club, undated (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0223 - UA30010071-N-0256)
  - Duke and Christmas, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0257 - UA30010071-N-0309)
  - Football pictures, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0310 - UA30010071-N-0325)
  - Snow pictures, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0326 - UA30010071-N-0390)
  - Elizabeth Hatcher, Bob Conner, others, undated (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0391 - UA30010071-N-0396)
  - Football pictures, undated (Box 5, Image UA30010071-N-0397)
  - Football pictures, undated (Box 6, Image UA30010071-N-0398 - UA30010071-N-0400)
  - Crowd at train station, undated (Box 6, Image UA30010071-N-0401 - UA30010071-N-0405)
  - Winters, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Image UA30010071-N-0406 - UA30010071-N-0417)
  - Outdoor scenes, undated (Box 6, Image UA30010071-N-0418 - UA30010071-N-0421)
- Memorabilia, correspondence, diary, and scrapbook
  - Invitations, postcards, bill/receipt, 1935, undated (Box 1)
  - Bob Conner's letters to his mother, 1933-1938 (Box 1)
  - Explorer's Club roster and Duke Fight Song lyrics, undated (Box 1)
  - Duke in Portrait Calendar, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Bob Conner orchid collection diary, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Newsclippings, circa 1930s (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1936-1937 (Box 2)
  - Bob Conner's dink (freshman beanie), circa 1933-1937 (Box 3)